ROHIT KUMAR

Backend ∼ Developer

rohitkumar.com

gmrohitkumar@gmail.com

**** 7007814974

github.com/geniusrks1

Faizabad, India

in /in/rohit-kumar-483091161

SUMMARY

Innovative Full Stack Web Developer (MERN STACK), with experience in creating beautiful and Responsive web applications with decent user interfaces. I also have experience in deploying websites on FireBase. Apart from these, I am also a Question Solver based on Data Structure in Java, having excellence certificate in both of these fields from Coding Ninjas.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C.

Technologies: MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React,

Node.js), Firebase

PROJECTS

MEN STACK E-COMMERCE

github link

Explore our e-commerce site powered by MongoDB, Express.js, and Node.js. Shop securely with diverse products, easy navigation, and seamless transactions.

React-Firebase

E-COMMERCE

github link

Seamless ecommerce experience with login, Redux integration, advanced filtering, and efficient cart management.

React-Firebase

Expense-Tracker

github link

Manage your finances effortlessly with our React.js expense tracker app. Secure, intuitive, and convenient budgeting powered by Firebase integration.

Socket.io

My Chat App

github link

Experience real-time communication with our Express, is chat app,

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016 **IIT(ISM) DHANBAD**

B.TECH

ISM Dhanbad ECE graduate. Strong in electronics and communication engineering. Passionate about technology, innovation, and problem-solving.

2018 - 2020

IIT BHU

M.TECH

IIT BHU Material Science and Technology post graduate. Expertise in advanced materials, research, and innovation. Committed to excellence and cutting-edge discoveries.

2021 - 2022

Certificate

Skill

Skilled in DSA with Java and frontend development from Coding Ninjas. Passionate about problem-solving and creativity. LINK

2022 - 2023

Certificate

Skill

Enthusiastically mastering competitive programming techniques and MERN stack development. Dedicated to enhancing problem-solving skills and building versatile web applications. LINK

EXPERIENCE

2016 - 2018

Operating Head

EZTech-Solution

 Strategic leader in a startup, optimizing processes, managing teams. Specializing in seamless online exam solutions, ensuring secure platforms, exceptional user experiences.

2022-2023

Teaching Assistant

Coding Ninjas

Assisting students with data structures and algorithms, resolving doubts effectively, fostering understanding, and enhancing problem-solving skills through personalized guidance.
JAVA / DSA

2020 -

Founder and Developer

EZGamingWorld.com

 Founder and developer of EZGamingWorld.com, crafting innovative online gaming experiences. Passionate about gaming technology, user engagement, and immersive gameplay.

1

LANGUAGES